{
    "glossary": {
        "title": "1982",
        "season": "Vår",
        "glossaryList":[
            {
                "number": "1",
                "question": "stadfästa",
                "a": "godkänna",
                "b": "upplysa",
                "c": "anbringa",
                "d": "tillägga",
                "e": "utveckla",
                "answer": "godkänna"
            },
            {
                "number": "2",
                "question": "kuperad",
                "a": "hård",
                "b": "krokig",
                "c": "ojämn",
                "d": "rundad",
                "e": "brokig",
                "answer": "ojämn"
            },
            {
                "number": "3",
                "question": "nautik",
                "a": "sjövetenskap",
                "b": "nakenkultur",
                "c": "växtfärgning",
                "d": "naturbeskrivning",
                "e": "flygkonst",
                "answer": "sjövetenskap"
            },
            {
                "number": "4",
                "question": "ajournera",
                "a": "uppnå",
                "b": "uppskjuta",
                "c": "upplysa",
                "d": "uppmana",
                "e": "uppsöka",
                "answer": "uppskjuta"
            },
            {
                "number": "5",
                "question": "rubank",
                "a": "stege",
                "b": "hyvel",
                "c": "skål",
                "d": "båt",
                "e": "uthus",
                "answer": "hyvel"
            },
            {
                "number": "6",
                "question": "gourmet",
                "a": "drömtydare",
                "b": "bedragare",
                "c": "beskyddare",
                "d": "upprorsmakare",
                "e": "finsmakare",
                "answer": "finsmakare"
            },
            {
                "number": "7",
                "question": "enkät",
                "a": "kallelse",
                "b": "anteckning",
                "c": "rundfråga",
                "d": "ansökan",
                "e": "tillstånd",
                "answer": "rundfråga"
            },
            {
                "number": "8",
                "question": "konträr",
                "a": "motsatt",
                "b": "omstridd",
                "c": "ogiltig",
                "d": "besvärlig",
                "e": "påtaglig",
                "answer": "motsatt"
            },
            {
                "number": "9",
                "question": "syntes",
                "a": "ersättning",
                "b": "kännetecken",
                "c": "beställning",
                "d": "förslag",
                "e": "sammanställning",
                "answer": "sammanställning"
            },
            {
                "number": "10",
                "question": "respons",
                "a": "avslag",
                "b": "avsked",
                "c": "svar",
                "d": "frist",
                "e": "förfrågan",
                "answer": "svar"
            },
            {
                "number": "11",
                "question": "suggerera",
                "a": "påverka",
                "b": "ersätta",
                "c": "befalla",
                "d": "utnyttja",
                "e": "understödja",
                "answer": "påverka"
            },
            {
                "number": "12",
                "question": "fjärma",
                "a": "avlägsna",
                "b": "bortförklara",
                "c": "sammanföra",
                "d": "anvisa",
                "e": "begränsa",
                "answer": "avlägsna"
            },
            {
                "number": "13",
                "question": "hybris",
                "a": "lockelse",
                "b": "inbilskhet",
                "c": "sans",
                "d": "utsträlning",
                "e": "övermod",
                "answer": "övermod"
            },
            {
                "number": "14",
                "question": "blase",
                "a": "gammalmodig",
                "b": "uppmärksam",
                "c": "nedlåtande",
                "d": "likgiltig",
                "e": "klumpig",
                "answer": "likgiltig"
            },
            {
                "number": "15",
                "question": "aura",
                "a": "spira",
                "b": "sken",
                "c": "rökelse",
                "d": "spådom",
                "e": "doft",
                "answer": "spira"
            },
            {
                "number": "16",
                "question": "hemisfär",
                "a": "stjärnbild",
                "b": "halvklot",
                "c": "pol",
                "d": "fixstjärna",
                "e": "norrsken",
                "answer": "halvklot"
            },
            {
                "number": "17",
                "question": "påtala",
                "a": "försäkra",
                "b": "bevisa",
                "c": "kräva",
                "d": "beställa",
                "e": "kritisera",
                "answer": "kritisera"
            },
            {
                "number": "18",
                "question": "preferera",
                "a": "förestå",
                "b": "förelägga",
                "c": "föredra",
                "d": "företaga",
                "e": "föregripa",
                "answer": "föredra"
            },
            {
                "number": "19",
                "question": "kuriös",
                "a": "framstående",
                "b": "allvarlig",
                "c": "underlig",
                "d": "misstänksam",
                "e": "vardaglig",
                "answer": "underlig"
            },
            {
                "number": "20",
                "question": "ambivalens",
                "a": "upprördhet",
                "b": "självmedvetenhet",
                "c": "överkänslighet",
                "d": "underlägsenhet",
                "e": "kluvenhet",
                "answer": "kluvenhet"
            },
            {
                "number": "21",
                "question": "maxim",
                "a": "lag",
                "b": "tecken",
                "c": "avtal",
                "d": "grundsats",
                "e": "rådslag",
                "answer": "grundsats"
            },
            {
                "number": "22",
                "question": "konvergera",
                "a": "komma tillbaka",
                "b": "löpa ihop",
                "c": "gå isär",
                "d": "komma överens",
                "e": "avsäga sig",
                "answer": "löpa ihop"
            },
            {
                "number": "23",
                "question": "järtecken",
                "a": "varsel",
                "b": "hänvisning",
                "c": "bekräftelse",
                "d": "adelsmärke",
                "e": "släktdrag",
                "answer": "varsel"
            },
            {
                "number": "24",
                "question": "jävig",
                "a": "lämplig",
                "b": "föraktfull",
                "c": "högljudd",
                "d": "fridsam",
                "e": "obehörig",
                "answer": "obehörig"
            },
            {
                "number": "25",
                "question": "kantele",
                "a": "soffa",
                "b": "vagn",
                "c": "musikstycke",
                "d": "blomma",
                "e": "instrument",
                "answer": "instrument"
            },
            {
                "number": "26",
                "question": "plausibel",
                "a": "löjlig",
                "b": "verklig",
                "c": "känslig",
                "d": "sannolik",
                "e": "tråkig",
                "answer": "sannolik"
            },
            {
                "number": "27",
                "question": "syndrom",
                "a": "vanföreställning",
                "b": "sjukdomsbild",
                "c": "världsbild",
                "d": "gängbildning",
                "e": "trosriktning",
                "answer": "sjukdomsbild"
            },
            {
                "number": "28",
                "question": "sentens",
                "a": "motsats",
                "b": "tänkespråk",
                "c": "uppslag",
                "d": "förutsägelse",
                "e": "andel",
                "answer": "tänkespråk"
            },
            {
                "number": "29",
                "question": "didaktisk",
                "a": "spetsfundig",
                "b": "uppsluppen",
                "c": "undervisande",
                "d": "beräknande",
                "e": "skiljaktig",
                "answer": "undervisande"
            },
            {
                "number": "30",
                "question": "relevant",
                "a": "föränderlig",
                "b": "smidig",
                "c": "betydelsefull",
                "d": "tålig",
                "e": "motståndskraftig",
                "answer": "betydelsefull"
            }
        ]
    }
}